《絕命律師》前請提要
Previouly, on "Better Call Saul."
要么給我錢  要么我倆都別想活著走出這里
I get my money, or neither of us walk out of here.
只要我一句話
I say the word,
我的侄子們就會去拜訪你的小孫女
my nephews pay a visit to your granddaughter.
我不想再聽到"許可證"這個詞  明白嗎
I don't ever want to hear the word "Permit" Again! Capiche?
你會遭報應的  哥們
It's your funeral, dude!
你被炒了
You're fired!
我去收拾東西
I'll just pack up...
你和我一起合伙
Partners, you and me!
哪里來的委托人呢
What about clients?
梅薩維德
Mesa Verde.
想把他們挖走很難
It'd be a hard sell to take them with me.
同一屋檐下兩間律所
Separate firms under one roof.
你按你的方式來  我按我的來
You... do things your way, and I do them mine.
冰淇淋
往前
Ahead.
左轉
Turn to the left.
到卡車后面來
Step around the back of the truck.
行了
Okay.
給
Here you go.
絕命律師
第二季 第八集
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
我本來想帶你去個
You know, I was willing to take you
翻譯  TheWalkingNerd  喵球球  肉松
更高端的地方
to a more high-end establishment.
這值得好好慶祝一番
This requires a proper celebration,
所以這一餐不算
so don't think that this counts.
翻譯  joy_bwl  酸奶  西陵折枝
熱狗屋
這很完美了
This is perfect.
再說...
Besides...
校對  喃喃
我們現在得省吃儉用
we're pinching pennies now.
等我們有了穩定的收入
When we have a steady revenue stream,
時間軸   今  夢龍
每晚都要開到杰洛尼莫去吃飯
make the drive up ‭to Geronimo every night.
-在那之前...  -沒錯
- Till then... - ‭Yes. That.
一起實現這愿望吧
Let's make that happen.
后期  深山小新    總監  喃喃
你接下來就這樣
Okay, here's what ya gotta do.
打開微信   掃描左側二維碼
或搜索公眾號:    美劇炸了
了解最新影視資訊字幕信息
馬上寫好你的辭職信
Type up ‭your resignation letter now --
-今晚搞定  -今晚
- I mean, tonight. - ‭Tonight?
對
‭Yeah.
當然是先吃完你的熱狗...
Well, I mean, finish your hot dog first, but...
今天晚上就把辭職信放到霍華德的辦公室
Now, you put that letter into Howard's office tonight.
算是在他的地盤上正式通知他
It's on his premises. You've officially given notice.
明天早上
Tomorrow morning,
他打高爾夫打得不亦樂乎時
while he's still out on the back nine chasin' his balls,
你就打給梅薩維德  和其他的委托人
you call Mesa Verde and your other clients,
把他們拉過來
you bring 'em along.
得比他先下手
You get to them before he does.
-不行  -什么  不
- No. ‭- What? No.
你必須現在行動
You gotta act now.
你如果用"正確方法"
Listen, ‭you do this the "Right way,"
等著當面告訴霍華德
you wait, ‭you tell Howard to his face,
他會在你說出"辭職"兩字前
he'll sink his dirty hooks into Mesa Verde
就向梅薩維德伸出魔爪
before you get the words "I quit" outta your mouth.
夠了吉米  很感謝你的建議
Okay, Jimmy, I appreciate the advice,
但重點是
but the whole point of this
你當你的律師  我當我的
is for you to be your kind of lawyer and me to be mine.
我需要對我而言正確的方法
I need to find a way to do this that's right for me.
你好  金  能長話短說嗎
Hey, Kim. Can we make this quick?
我有點忙不過來了
I'm kinda swamped right now.
當然  謝謝你抽空見我
Uh, sure. ‭Thanks for meeting with me.
我只需要占用幾分鐘
I only need a few minutes.
很好  什么事
Great. What's up?
霍華德  我們能到你辦公室里說嗎
Howard, ‭could we do this in your office?
拜托
Please?
再次感謝你抽空
Again, ‭thanks for taking the time.
你沒必要拐彎抹角
You can just... go ahead ‭and rip off the Band-Aid.
我大概知道你來這里的目的
I have a pretty good idea why you're here.
那么  你選擇去斯韋卡特和考科利
So, you're going with Schweikart and Cokely.
-什么  -我聽說了
- I'm sorry? - ‭I heard.
小道消息
Through the grapevine.
我不去其他律所
I'm not going to another firm.
我要自立門戶
I'm starting my own.
我打算嘗試個體律師
I figured I'd try giving it a go as a solo practitioner.
我...
I, uh...
我意識到這是我該做的
I realized it was something I needed to do.
?吉米離開戴維斯梅因律所的同一周
The week ‭Jimmy exits Davis & Main,
你也決定要離開我們
you decide to leave us?
這不可能是巧合
That can't just be happenstance.
不是
It's not.
我們會分攤支出
We're gonna be sharing expenses.
共用辦公室  但是兩人獨立執業
One office, ‭but two separate practices.
各方面看來都...很聰明
Smart -- on several counts.
霍華德
Howard...
我希望你知道  我很珍惜在這里的時間
I want you to know ‭that I appreciate my time here.
你和律所為我做的每件事我都感激不已
I'm grateful for everything you and the firm have done for me,
特別是支付我的學費
especially the financial help with my schooling,
我準備寫支票償還剩余的貸款
and I'm ready to write a check for the remainder of the loan.
只需要會計那邊給我確切金額
I just need accounting to get me that figure.
不用了  當作贈禮吧
No need. Our gift to you.
我不知道該說什么了
I don't know what to say.
謝謝你
Thank you.
你應得的
You earned it.
說實話  我有點羨慕
Tell you the truth, I'm kinda envious.
真的嗎  為什么
Really? Why?
新的開始
Something about a fresh start.
想當年  我剛從法學院畢業
Back in the day, right out of law school,
我慎重考慮過自己掛牌營業
I thought long and hard about hanging up my own shingle.
-真的嗎  -是的
- Oh, yeah? ‭- Yeah.
我已經準備好闖蕩世界  改變世界
Oh, I was ready to take on the world, make a difference.
老爸說服了我
Dad talked me out of it.
要我加入在這里的生意
Wanted me to join the ranks here,
在律所名里再加一個"H"
throw another "H" In the firm's logo.
一切都還算順利吧
Things work out the way they're supposed to, I guess.
金  我想告訴你  我總是對你施壓
Kim, I want you to know that I always pushed you harder
是因為我覺得你可以不斷突破自我
because I knew that I could expect more from you.
祝你好運
Good luck to you.
謝謝
Thank you.
幫我打給梅薩維德銀行的凱文·沃弛泰爾
Get me Kevin Wachtell at Mesa Verde.
取消今早所有安排
And cancel everything I had lined up this morning.
我這就打
Calling now.
不好意思
Sorry.
借過
Excuse me.
嗨  佩琪  我是金
Hi, Paige. It's Kim.
你好
Yeah, hi.
我想確認一下定在周一中午的午餐
Just checking that we're still on for lunch on Monday.
好極了  凱文也來嗎
Great. And Kevin, too?
好的
Good.
在見面之前
Well, before we meet,
我有個新情況要告訴你們
there's some news you need to know about.
我不是安全的選擇
I am not the safe choice.
安全的選擇是哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所
The safe choice for you would be HHM.
但是我覺得
I believe, however, that I am...
我才是正確的選擇
the right choice.
為什么
Why?
你現在穿的西裝是店里買的成衣嗎
That suit you're wearing -- did you buy it off the rack?
別告訴我這看上去像
Please don't tell me it looks like I did. ‭
如果像店里隨便買的  我就不會問了
If it did, I wouldn't have asked.
那為什么你要選擇訂做的呢
So why do you prefer a tailor-made suit?
因為那是最適合你的
Because it fits you and you alone.
每一針每一線都是為你考慮
Because each and every stitch was fretted over with you in mind.
要么你去適合西裝
Either you fit the jacket...
要么它適合你
or the jacket fits you.
如果我要一整個倉庫的西裝呢
What if I want ‭a whole warehouse full of suits?
需要很多人來縫制
That's a hell of a lot of sewing.
一個裁縫如何獨自完成這項任務呢
How's one single tailor gonna get that job done?
我完全了解你們銀行對于擴張的需求
I know your bank's needs in regard to this expansion inside and out.
梅薩維德作為我唯一的委托人
Having Mesa Verde as my sole client
一定會占用我全部的精力
will take up the entirety of my attention, to be sure.
但如果我不能勝任
But if this were beyond my abilities,
我就不會接
I wouldn't be ‭throwing my hat in the ring.
我不會浪費你們的時間
I would not waste your time,
以及我的時間
or mine.
你來啦  金  我們在里面
Oh, hey, Kim! We're in here!
來得正好  我正在看房
Perfect timing. ‭I was just getting the tour.
-金  這是史蒂夫  -你好
- Kim, this is Steve. - ‭Hi.
史蒂夫是這里的中介
Steve's the agent for the place.
-你好  我叫金  -見到你很高興
- Hi. Kim. ‭- Nice to meet ya.
-金  -一切還好嗎
- Hi, Kim. - ‭Everything okay?
怎么樣
What do you think?
我  我覺得這是個牙醫診所吧
I, uh... I think it's a -- it's a dentist's office.
兩間牙醫診室
Two offices for two dentists,
大小相同  陳設都是對稱的
each the exact same size with a mirrored layout.
來
Here.
另一間就在隔壁
The other one is the next door over,
兩個靠在一起
right beside this one.
就在這
Right here.
但是共用一個大廳
But they share one lobby,
一個接待區  相當平等
one reception area, so egalitarian as hell.
而且很高效
Not to mention efficient.
還有
Oh, also...
隔音墻壁
soundproof walls,
隔絕鉆子啊慘叫啊之類的聲音
what with the drilling and the pain and the whatnot.
還有這個地段  棒極了
And the location, I mean, holy crap.
我覺得就是這里了
I think this is the place.
金
Kim?
是啊  很好  隔音的
Yeah, it's great. Soundproofing.
史蒂夫  我們能不能單獨
Hey, Steve, do you mind if we just...?
沒事
Oh, please.
我出去打幾個電話
I'll step outside ‭and make some phone calls.
你們慢慢說
Y'all take all the time you need.
午飯不順利嗎
Bad lunch, huh?
梅薩維德拒絕了你嗎
Mesa Verde said no?
我弄不清情況了
Okay, I'm getting mixed signals here.
這是代表好的...
I-is this a good --
吉米  我搞定了
Jimmy, I got it.
-你搞定梅薩維德銀行了  -太好了
- You got Mesa Verde? ‭- Yes!
還沒簽正式文件
I mean, ‭there's nothing in writing yet,
但是午餐非常
but the lunch went...
非常順利
It kicked ass.
當時形勢確實有點危險
It was a little touch-and-go there for a moment, I'll admit,
但佩琪替我說話  幫了很大的忙
but Paige pitched in, and she really talked me up.
一等他松了口...
And then once ‭that door cracked open --
擊個掌  棒極了
High five. Fantastic. ‭
我對每一個問題和擔憂都準備了答案
I-I had an for answer question, every concern,
也完全沒說哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所的壞話
and I did not bad-mouth HHM, not at all,
但是我很有激情
but I was, like, enthusiasm, you know,
還有私人服務  肯定也因為這個
and personal service, because that's gotta count for something.
-當然了  -就是啊
- Shit, yeah, that counts! - ‭Exactly!
畢竟
I mean, 'cause, like,
他們一開始怎么會到哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所
why were they even at HHM in the first place?
還不是因為我  所以  我們走出餐館時
Me. So, uh -- Oh, and then when we walked out of the restaurant,
凱文看不見的時候  佩琪朝我豎大拇指
when Kevin wasn't looking, Paige gives me a thumbs-up.
不是普通的豎一根
But not -- ‭not the regular thumbs-up.
是兩根
The double thumbs-up.
兩個  雙筒槍
Two. ‭Double barrel.
砰砰  像這樣
Boom, boom. Just like that.
我就知道
I knew it.
-我就知道你可以的  -真是...
- I knew you could do it! - ‭It was just...
真是太好了
God, it was perfect.
怎么了
What?
我喜歡看到你現在的樣子
I just -- ‭I love seeing you like this.
我們要留著這些椅子嗎
So, are we gonna keep these chairs?
你是說你喜歡這個辦公室嗎
Does that mean you like this office?
咱們就這么辦吧
Let's do it.
沒問題
Hell, yeah.
就這么辦吧
Let's do it.
歐內斯托  門沒鎖
Ernesto, the door's open...
像往常一樣
...as always.
歐內斯托
Ernesto?
是我  查克
It's me, Chuck.
霍華德  歐內斯托和你一起嗎
Oh, hey, Howard, is Ernesto with you?
沒有  只有我
No, it's just me.
我等文件等了一個小時了
Well, I expected a round of documents an hour ago.
我們馬上要去立案了
You know ‭we've got a filing coming up.
我知道  查克
I know, Chuck.
我們很有可能...
It's very possible...
我們可能要失去梅薩維德銀行了
It's likely ‭that we're losing Mesa Verde.
失去  我們剛剛才拿下他們
Losing them? We just got them.
為什么  他們打算去找誰
Well, why? Where are they going?
去找金·韋克斯勒
They're going with Kim Wexler.
她職辭了
‭She left the firm.
金辭職了
Kim left?
霍華德
Oh, Howard.
她要去哪里
Well, where's she going?
里奇·斯韋卡特那里嗎
Is it Rich Schweikart?
還是里夫斯和格林公司
Or did Reeves and Green get her?
都不是  不是跳槽
Mnh. Not another firm.
她要單干了
She's going into private practice.
什么
What?
這真是...
Well, that's completely...
她要怎么自己單干呢
H-how is she going out on her own?
她為什么要單干呢
Why is she going out on her own?
沒什么原因
Well, the why is the why.
至于怎么干  她正準備和吉米聯手
The how is that ‭she's pooling her resources... with Jimmy.
金和我弟弟  成了合伙人嗎
Kim and my brother -- partners at law?
他是斯文加利
He's Svengali.
小說《特里比》中的人物  用催眠術控制女主人公
這家伙是個催眠大師
The man is Svengali.
不管怎樣  關于梅薩維德銀行
At any rate, back to Mesa Verde.
我打算孤注一擲
I'm gonna try one last Hail Mary.
查克
Uh, Chuck?
-梅薩維德銀行  -我聽著呢
- Mesa Verde. - ‭Yes, listening.
我爭取了一個和凱文·沃弛泰爾見面的機會
I managed to get a meeting with Kevin Wachtell.
他下午到
He's coming in this afternoon.
但我不是很清楚該遵從哪些法
But compliance law is not my strong suit.
所以如果你有任何論點論據
So if you have any details, any arguments,
現在趕快告訴我
bullet-point them for me now,
我只有一個小時的時間
'cause I got about an hour before I have to get back.
查克
Chuck?
我真的很需要你的幫助
I really need your help here.
查克
Chuck?
你還好吧
Are you okay?
我也去參加會議
I'm going to that meeting.
查克  這樣也許不好吧
Chuck, I don't know if that's a good idea.
我可以的
I can do it.
我會靠意志力堅持
Force of will.
而且我已經好多了
And I've been getting better.
我知道  但是...
I know you have, but...
想想我們要傳遞的信息
the message that we want to send.
我懂
I know the message --
要表現得專業  而不是瘋狂
that we appear professional and not crazy!
我要去開會  燈給我開著
I'm going to the meeting and the lights stay on.
大家都帶著手機
Everyone keeps their phones.
一切正常就行
Everything stays, for lack of a better word, normal.
我會挺過來的
I will make it through.
請進
‭Yeah?
他們到了
They're here.
好的
Okay.
大家好
Hello, everyone.
-抱歉我來晚了  -你們好
- Sorry I was delayed. - Oh. Hi.
不不  完全沒有  我們剛坐下
No, no. Not at all. We just sat down.
凱文·沃弛泰爾  佩奇·諾維克
Kevin Wachtell, Paige Novick,
這位是查爾斯·麥吉爾
this is Charles McGill.
叫我查克就好
Chuck.
很高興見到你們  凱文  佩奇
Pleasure. Kevin. Paige.
很高興見到你
Nice to meet you.
感謝你們兩位前來
Thank you both for coming.
別擔心
And don't worry.
請二位來不是來聽我吹噓HHM的
I'm not here ‭to extol the virtues of HHM.
我猜你們已經受夠了
‭I'm guessing you've already had to suffer through
霍華德對于律所的強行推銷了
Howard's hard sell first time around,
依我看  你們已經聽夠了
so you've done your time, as far ‭as I'm concerned.
才不是強行推銷  那只是熱情待客
What hard sell? It was enthusiasm.
我還給他們拿了餅干呢
I gave them cookies.
我記得餅干還挺好吃的
Cookies were good, as I recall.
我今天來是想讓你們放心
No, I'm here to put your minds at ease.
金·韋克斯勒
Kim Wexler is,
的確是處理梅薩維德業務的不二人選
indeed, the right choice to handle Mesa Verde.
選擇她很明智
She's the obvious choice.
她年輕又聰明  前途無量
She's young, she's brilliant, she's going places.
咱們面對現實吧  霍華德
Let's face it, Howard.
她才是未來
She's the future.
像我倆這種老人家  已經過時了
Two old guys like us, we're the past.
真是讓人悲傷的看法
Well, that's a sad thought.
悲傷但真實
‭Sad but true.
銀行法...需要激情
Banking law... needs to be exciting.
需要下一代崛起的新秀
It needs the next generation to come along
為它注入新鮮血液
and give it a big, old kick in the seat of the pants.
真正喚醒它
Really wake it up.
我告訴你們我有多無聊
Let me tell ya how boring I am.
我靠讀FEC和ISO報告來打發時間
I read FEC and ISO reports for entertainment.
沒錯  我能證明
He does. I can attest to that.
我想努力跟上潮流
Well, I try to stay up on things.
規則時刻在改變
The rules are changing all the time.
安然和世通出事了以后
With everything that's happened with Enron and WorldCom,
政府格外警惕
the government is extra vigilant.
現在  即便是最無心的過錯
These days, the penalties for even the most honest
也可能招致毀滅性的后果
of errors can be devastating.
你需要年輕敏銳的眼光把握這些動向
You need a sharp, ‭young eye to catch that stuff.
當你已經在這個領域
I mean, when you've specialized in this kind of work
縱橫了十多年  就會變得有點...
for decades on end, you tend to get kinda...
-陳腐  -陳腐
- Stale. ‭- Stale.
你會變得很陳腐
You get stale.
你會忘掉那些  譬如
You forget about things like, oh, I don't know,
《社區再投資法案》
the Community Reinvestment Act.
像梅薩維德銀行這樣想設新支行的銀行
Any bank such as Mesa Verde looking to open a de novo branch
必須展現符合該法案的
is definitely going to need to show a healthy portfolio
健康投資組合
of CRA compliance.
當然是開玩笑的了
Duh. Obviously.
我相信這方面你們肯定都做好了
You guys have all that covered, I'm sure.
《里格-尼爾州際銀行和分行效益法》
Riegle-Neal Interstate Banking and Branching Efficiency Act --
真是拗口啊
there's another mouthful, huh?
無聊
Boring!
不過如果你違反該法律
Still, ‭if you were to run afoul of it,
可能得打上好幾年官司
it could hold you up in court for years.
順便  如果你們在沒有我們的情況下
And by the way, uh, if that were to happen to you folks
發生這種事  不過當然不會了
as you go forward without us, which it will not, um,
霍華德在美聯儲有人能夠幫忙處理這些事
Howard has contacts at the Fed who could help sort things out.
一兩個吧
One or two.
還有證券交易委員會對
And then there's the SEC's interpretation
《薩奧法案》302節的闡釋
of Section 302 of Sarbox.
小心行事
Well, navigating that correctly
可以省下好幾十萬呢
could mean savings of several hundred thousand dollars.
他們很清楚呢  霍華德
They know that, Howard.
抱歉
Aapologize.
人到了一定歲數
When you reach your golden years,
就會變得有點啰啰嗦嗦
you tend ‭to get a little long-winded,
老是念叨著一些細節
ramble on and on about details.
我想說的是  你的銀行在可靠的人手上
My point being, ‭your bank is in excellent hands.
我明白你想說什么  真的
Look, I take your point. I do.
但我要說
But I have to say,
我對韋克斯勒女士很有信心
I have complete confidence in Ms. Wexler.
你是該如此
You should.
她在我們團隊中待過
She was part of our team.
她師從我們
She learned from us.
找不到比金·韋克斯勒更合適的人選了
You won't find better than Kim Wexler.
但是不管她多么優秀
But no matter how talented one individual may be,
梅薩維德的業務太重  一個人沒法做
the needs of Mesa Verde are too big to handle alone.
我是不會單獨處理你們今后的擴張
I wouldn't handle ‭your coming expansion alone.
所以你應該再考慮一下
Which is why you should consider, once again,
交給我們這樣專業的團隊
enlisting a team of professionals.
-很高興能與你們見面  -隨時恭候
- Glad we did this. - ‭Any time.
我們時刻聽候你們的差遣
We are there for you day and night.
很高興見到你  佩奇
Lovely to meet you, Paige.
我也是  謝謝
And you. Thank you.
回見  先生們
Talk soon, gentlemen.
查克  那...
Chuck, that...
真是太棒了
That was amazing.
你真是太棒了
You were fantastic.
真...查克
Trul-- Whoa. Chuck?
送我回家
Get me home.
歐尼
Ernie! ‭
撐住
Hang on.
我們還是要謝謝你
Again, we want to thank you
能夠接待少校
for accommodating the Major like this.
開什么玩笑  這是我的榮幸
You kidding? It's an honor.
為了戰爭英雄  可以小小地破個例
For a war hero, I think we can bend the rules a wee bit.
真的很感謝你
Well, we really appreciate it.
塔爾博特少校的孫子只在城里再留一天
Major Talbott's grandsons are only in town for one more day,
他們能跟他一起分享這次經歷真是太好了
so it's great they get to share this experience with him.
這將是你們永生難忘的經歷
You guys are in for a real treat.
激動嗎
You excited?!
是啊  很激動
Y-yeah, excited.
他們是你兒子嗎
So, these are your boys?
不  我...我是他們家的律師
No, I'm -- No, I'm the family attorney.
能幫就幫一把  所以我打給了你
I just help when I can, so I called you.
很高興為你們效勞
Well, ‭I am glad to be of service.
就是她了
And here she is.
先生們  這是菲菲
Gentlemen, meet FIFI,
世界上最后一架在任B29超級空中堡壘
the world's last ‭air-worthy B-29 Superfortress.
原本在德州基地  但是暫時飛到這兒
She's based in Texas, but she's here for a quick visit,
鼓舞飛行員的士氣
just kind of a morale builder for the airmen.
不過大家現在正在吃午飯
The crew's on lunch, unfortunately.
不然我還想帶你們看一下內部
Otherwise, I was gonna see about showing you the inside.
很美吧  "軟糖"
Isn't she a beauty, Fudge?
就像你以前開過的飛機一樣
Just like the one you used to fly.
-軟糖  -沒錯
- Fudge? - Yep.
西奧多·"軟糖"·塔爾博特少校
Major Theodore "Fudge" Talbott.
他的媽媽在戰爭期間
His mom used to mail him
會給他寄軟糖愛心包裹
care packages of fudge during the war,
他會分給他的朋友
and he shared them with his friends.
的確是這樣吧  伙計們
So that's the story. Right, guys?
-是啊  -是的
- Yes. - ‭Yeah.
先生  這一定勾起你的記憶了
Well, sir, this certainly must bring back some memories for you.
他說"太多了"
"Too many to count," He says.
我得說塔爾博特少校
I gotta say, Major Talbott...
這是我的榮幸
it's a privilege.
感謝您為國家效力
So thank you for your service.
他說"你客氣了"
He says, "You're welcome."
我真羨慕你們
Boy, I envy you guys.
你們一定聽過他的故事
I mean, the stories you must've heard.
有哪些不錯的故事嗎
You remember any good ones?
-大多是關于轟炸的  -關于轟炸
- Bombing stuff mostly. - Bombing stuff.
比如戰爭
Um, like, um -- like, the war.
他飛越過喜馬拉雅嗎
Did he fly over the Hump,
或者從印度起飛過嗎
or did he take off out of India?
你沒事吧  你要喝水嗎
You doing okay? You need some water?
好  好的
Yes. Yes, sir.
我忘帶他的水了
Oh, nuts. I forgot his water.
我可以回辦公室給他拿一瓶
Oh, hey. I can run back to the office, get him a bottle.
可以嗎
You could?
軟糖  上尉說他要回辦公室
Fudge, the captain's gonna run back to his office,
給你拿點水  好嗎長官
get you some water, okay, sir?
好的  太棒了
All right. That's great.
不用著急  他沒事
And there's no rush. He's gonna be fine.
我盡快回來
I'll be back ASAP.
起來  起來
Up. Up.
跟你說了什么都別說
Thought I told you not to say anything.
站到前面去  機頭那  隨便吧
Go stand by the front, uh, those nose, whatever.
你到底從哪找來這家伙的
Where the hell'd you find this guy?
你找不到真正的戰爭英雄嗎
You couldn't get a real war hero?
你以為這么好找  這家伙欠我的
Yeah, like they grow on trees. So, this guy owes me.
他沒錢的時候我幫他辯護
I defended him a while back when he couldn't pay.
-為他辯護什么  -怎么
- Defended him for what? - What?
你長大想當律師嗎
You wanna be a lawyer when you grow up?
固定那...
Just fix the --
公共場合自慰
Public masturbation.
簡直胡說八道
Total bullshit.
好了  聲音小點
All right, keep your voice down.
你沒有話語權
You do not possess the power of speech.
好  開始吧
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
快點
Chop chop.
好  雙手叉腰
All right, hands on hips.
行嗎  表現得強壯驕傲
All right? Looking strong, looking proud, all right?
拍轟炸機  轟炸機是重點  拍它
See the bomber, okay? The bomber's the main point, so see it.
我在拍那該死的轟炸機了
I see the freaking bomber.
就不能把這家伙放國旗前嗎
Couldn't just plop the dude in front of a flag?
為什么非要來這
Why'd we have to come here?
因為制作水準要高  要表演
Production value. Showmanship.
開拍了嗎
You rolling?
-是的  在拍了  -在拍了
- Yeah, rolling. - Rolling.
好  開始推鏡
Okay, start the dolly.
開始
And action.
你是最偉大的一代人
You're part ‭of the greatest generation.
你打過納粹
You fought the Nazis.
打過日本人
Fought the Japanese.
-什么  -我打過日本人
- What? ‭- Fought Japanese.
我打過日本人
I fought the Japanese.
這飛機曾用于太平洋戰場
This machine was used in the Pacific,
就用來打日本
where the Japanese are.
你為什么不閉嘴聽指示
Why don't you shut up and learn to take some direction?
一百英尺內禁煙
打的日本人
Japanese.
好  好
All right, fine.
你打過所有骯臟的軸心國
You fought all the dirty... Axis powers.
你們一群弟兄團結起來
Your band of brothers came together,
拯救了世界
and you saved the world.
你是個大英雄
You're heroic.
有點過了
Not that heroic.
表現出一點就行了
Just throw it away a little more.
好  很好
Okay, good.
愛國之情在你血液中奔馳
You've got red, white, and blue coursing through your veins.
看上面
Look up!
看見一只禿鷹直沖云霄
Picture a bald eagle soaring!
該死
‭Shit.
-怎么了  -你們繼續拍
- What? - ‭Okay, just keep rolling.
特寫  廣角都行  拍出好角度就行
Tights, wides -- just get me some good angles.
好  回到原點
Okay. All right, back to one.
回到原點  軟糖
Back to one. Fudge.
軟糖  看這里  軟糖
Fudge, right here. Fudge.
什么事  歐尼
What is it, Ernie?
吉米  我在你哥這  他情況不妙
Jimmy, man, I'm at your brother's, and he's bad.
不妙  有多不妙
Bad? How bad?
他...我說不清  就是不妙  不停發抖
He's -- I don't know. Bad, shakin'.
我從沒見過他這樣
I've never seen him like this.
一直告訴我別找醫生
He keeps telling me not to call a doctor.
讓我猜猜
Lemme guess.
他去辦公室了
He's been going into the office.
是的  而且
Yeah, more and more.
他今天開了一個重要的會議
He had ‭a big meeting there today.
好的  你這么做
Okay, ‭here's what you're gonna do.
用太空毯把他裹住
Wrap him in a space blanket.
他已經裹了一層了
He's already under one.
再裹一層
Wrap him in a second one.
給他點茶  或者最好給他熱點雞湯
Make him some tea, or just, better, heat some chicken broth.
小火慢燉
Just let it simmer.
不要煮沸
Don't make it boil.
就這樣  不用找醫生嗎
That's it? No doctor?
就這樣  不用醫生  他會挺過去的
That's it. No doctor. He's just gotta ride this out.
查克會沒事的
Chuck'll be fine.
該死  我得走了
Oh sh-- I gotta go.
大黃  大黃
Rhubarb. Rhubarb!
傻瓜  那是暗號
Idiots, that's the signal.
讓他坐輪椅上
Get him in the chair.
輸氧管呢  插進你鼻子
Where's the air hose? Stick it in your nose.
快
Come on.
長官
Sir!
不用這么麻煩你們
Hey, this is not a problem.
介意我們跟你拍張照嗎
Would you mind if the guys and I took a picture with you?
這對我們意義重大
It would mean a lot to us.
行  拍照  他愛拍照
Yeah, uh, p-pictures. He loves pictures.
來  給我相機
Here. Give me the camera.
-我來拍  -給你水
- I'll take it. - Here's your water.
-謝謝  -非常感謝
- Thank you, sir. - Thank you so much.
-謝謝  -沒問題
- Thank you. - Yeah. Ooh, here.
行  把你推過去
All right, let's scoot ya in.
轉過去
Swing ya around.
大家都站好
Okay, everybody line up?
笑
Smile.
茄子
Cheese.
你準備簽了嗎  來簽吧
You ready to sign? Let's do this.
怎么
What?
梅薩維德銀行跑了
I lost Mesa Verde.
-什么  -我之前說服他了
- What? - ‭I had him.
我以為說服了
I thought I had him.
怎么回事
‭So what happened?
他們繼續和哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所合作
They're s-sticking with HHM.
佩奇說他們今天下午過去
Paige said they went over there this afternoon
進行出于禮貌的會面
for some kind of... courtesy meeting,
反正她是這么以為  凱文改變想法了
or so she thought, ‭and Kevin got his head turned.
-霍華德說服的嗎  -不
- By Howard? - ‭No.
查克
Chuck.
吉米  我得問
Jimmy, I have to ask.
你還想這么做嗎
You still up for doing this?
你說租下辦公室嗎
What? You mean getting the office?
這一切
All of it.
我想我們也許得
I think maybe we need to...
放慢腳步  好好...
slow down and really, you know...
考慮這事
think about this.
等等
Wait. Whoa.
-都沒變  -都沒變嗎
- Nothing's changed. - N-nothing's changed?
我們馬上要簽下非常貴的租約
We're about to sign a very expensive lease
但一大筆收入已經不翼而飛了
after a very sizable chunk of income just went flying out the window.
這就是團隊的意義
That's why we're a team.
這種事總會發生
Something like this happens --
你幫我  我幫你
you're there to help me, I'm there to help you.
還會有梅薩維德這種大客戶的
There will be other Mesa Verdes.
你還是想繼續嗎
So you still wanna do this?
吉米...
Jimmy...
我完全按你說的做
I did everything you said,
但他并未好轉
but he's not getting any better.
你做得很好  歐尼
You did good, Ernie.
謝謝
Thanks.
你回家休息一下吧
Why don't you, uh, ‭go home and get some sleep?
我來接手
I'll take over.
他說想讓我留下
He told me he wanted me to stay.
沒關系  我來了
It's okay. I'm here now.
你下次見霍華德時
And, uh, next time you see Howard,
告訴他你要大大加薪
tell him you need a raise -- a big one.
查克  兄弟
Chuck, buddy?
感覺如何
‭How you feeling?
梅薩維德
怎么樣
Hey, how's it going?
我需要美工刀  尺子  要木頭的
I need an X-ACTO knife, a ruler -- wood, please --
錘磨機優質紙  約九千克  五百張
Hammermill Premium paper -- 20 pound, one ream --
還有固體膠
and a glue stick.
我要用最好的復印機
Oh, and point me to your best copier.
-最好的復印機  -沒錯  最好的復印機
- Best copier? - ‭Yeah. Best copier.
快  時間很緊
C'mon. Di di mau.
*這個禮拜  依舊古怪*
*Been a strange old week*
*未做之事  遇見之人*
*With the stuff you didn't do and the people that you meet*
*挖掘信息  就像拔牙*
*And digging up the words like pulling teeth*
*一副面孔  一個數字*
*Got a face, a number*
*以及她使用的化名*
*And a name that she goes under*
*也許這已相當不錯*
*I guess there's plenty worse place to be*
*那你為何不干*
*So why don't you do it*
*Yeah, why don't you do it*
*多多享樂  又有何妨*
*Ain't no harm in having just a bit more fun*
*無論自己  喜不喜歡*
*Whether you like it or not*
*永遠別擺  一副臭臉*
*Make no place for dragging down your face*
*難道不清楚這是你最好的結果*
*Don't you know it's the best one that you got*
*那你為何不干*
*So why don't you do it*
*Yeah, why don't you do it*
*那你為何不干*
*Why don't you do it, ooh*
*Why don't you do it*
*搶劫銀行*
*Break that bank*
*你可能一無所獲*
*You never know, you might draw blanks*
*然后還被繩之以法*
*Then again, it might sort you out*
*那你為何不干  為何不干  為何不干*
*So why don't you do it, do it, do it, do it, do it, do it*
*為何不干*
*Do it*
他起來了
He emerges.
下午好
Good afternoon.
下午了嗎
Is it afternoon?
歐內斯托人呢
Where's Ernesto?
他應該留下來陪我的
He was supposed to stay with me.
別怪歐尼
Don't get mad at Ernie.
他花了一天中最好的時間
He spent the better part of a day
欣賞你烤土豆[裹錫紙]的表演
watching you do your impression of a baked potato.
我讓他回家去睡會
I told him to go home, get some shut eye.
你餓嗎
‭You hungry?
除了餅干還想吃點什么嗎
You want something besides crackers?
不用  我沒事
No, I'm fine.
等我的胃不難受了我自己弄點東西吃
I'll fix myself something after my stomach settles.
在外面待這么久
Really doing a number on yourself,
真把你傷得不輕
spending so much time out of the house.
你就非得這么干  是吧
You just had to do it, huh?
不能眼看著金挖走梅薩維德銀行
Couldn't stand ‭to let Kim have Mesa Verde.
就非得從她手上搶走
You had to swipe it from her.
我沒有搶走任何東西
I didn't swipe anything.
我們只是留住委托人
We retained our client.
你和霍華德甚至都沒聽說過這個銀行
You and Howard never even heard about Mesa Verde
是金把它捧到你們面前的
till Kim brought it to ya on a red velvet pillow.
我要去沖個澡  還有一堆工作要處理
I need a shower, and I've got a ton of work to do.
如果你想吵架  吉米
So if you're lookin' for a fight, Jimmy,
我實在沒心情和你吵
I just don't have it in me.
吉米
Jimmy.
謝謝你留下來陪我
Thanks for stayin' with me.
我們之間有積怨未解
I know we have our issues,
但是  如果我倆換一下
but if things were reversed,
我希望你知道  我也會一樣待你
I hope you know that I would do the same for you.
干得真不錯
You're doing a great job.
你以前做過這個嗎
You done this before?
沒有  沒做過這樣的
No, not like this,
不過我們在學校里學過分數
but we learned about fractions in school.
是嗎  什么分數
You did? What fractions?
二分之一英寸  四分之一英寸
1/2 inch, 1/4 inch,
八分之一英寸  十六分之一英寸
1/8 inch, 1/16 inch.
你知道嗎  我得承認
You know, I gotta tell ya,
我在你這個年紀的時候可沒你聰明
you are much smarter than I was when I was your age.
或許是你老師教得不夠好
Maybe you needed better teachers.
有可能
That could be.
能讓我來鉆嗎
Can I do the drill now?
你答應了的
You promised.
是呀  我是答應了
I did, didn't I?
好了  過來
Okay, get up here.
用重型工具的時候
Now, you're gonna have to wear these
得戴上這個
if you're gonna handle the heavy machinery.
你怎么不戴
W-why don't you have to wear them?
因為爺爺是大人  長大了就會變笨
Because Pop-Pop's a grown-up, and grown-ups get to be stupid.
好了  戴上
Now, put them on.
好的
All right.
這個很重  所以我來拿著
Now, I'm gonna hold this because it's heavy,
我說按扳柄的時候你就按  行嗎
but you pull the trigger when I say so, okay?
把手放上來
Now get your hand on it.
好了  拿好了嗎
All right, you got it?
準備好了
Ready.
好的  準備  按
All right, ready...set...pull.
干得好
Good job.
能再來幾次嗎
Can we do more? ‭
你幫我放好
You line them up for me.
在家嗎
Hello?!
我們在后面
We're back here.
這是在干什么
Wow. What's all this?
我們在做一個特制軟管
We're making a special hose.
特制軟管啊  看出來了
Yeah, that's a special hose, all right.
我每隔四分之三英寸做一個記號
I made marks every 3/4 inch,
然后爺爺在下面墊上一塊木頭
then Pop-Pop put a piece of wood down
這樣就不會劃到桌子了
so he doesn't ruin his table.
然后我們在標記號的地方鉆孔
Then we line up a drill, put the hole on the "X."
我要給外面的杜鵑花做個滴灌管
I needed a soaker ‭for the rhododendrons out back.
好了  爺爺要自己完成工作了
Well, Pop-Pop's gonna have to finish his project on his own,
我們得走了
because we have to go.
可我們還沒做完呢
But we're not done yet.
沒事  我會做好的
No, I'll finish up.
小公主  你已經幫了我很大的忙了
But you, young lady, were a big help.
抱抱
Give me a hug.
愛你  寶貝
Love you, girl.
-我也愛你  -謝謝  麥克
- Love you. ‭- Thanks, Mike.
對了  你周五還是有空的吧
Oh, you still good for Friday?
當然
Absolutely.
我到時候再找個東西讓她玩
I'll think of another project by then.
太好了  再見
Fantastic. Bye.
再見
Bye.
我午餐已經約了人了
I have a lunch date already.
-推了  -不能推
- Well, break it. - ‭I cannot break it.
能別碰我嗎
Will you take your hands off me?
你以為你在演正骨醫生嗎
What are you playing, osteopath?
別激動
Temper, temper.
沃爾特  你已經不是我的丈夫了
Oh, listen, Walter, you are no longer my husband
也不再是我的老板
and no longer my boss.
我以后也不會再為你工作了
And you're not gonna be my boss.
如果你滿足于當編輯和記者
Well, it would've worked out if you'd been satisfied
事情就不會這樣  可你就不
with just being editor and reporter, but not you.
你非要嫁給我  毀了這一切
You had to marry me, spoil everything.
我不滿足  那是我求的婚咯
I wasn't satisfied? I suppose I proposed to you.
差不多就是  你連著兩年
Well, you practically did, making goo-goo eyes at me
整天對我送秋波  直到我松口
for two years until I broke down.
"啊  沃爾特"
"Oh, Walter."
而且我那晚是喝醉了才向你求的婚
And I still claim I was tight the night I proposed to ya.
如果你是個紳士
If you'd have been a gentleman,
就該忘了那晚的事  可你就不
you'd have forgotten all about it, but not you.
你竟敢
Why, you!
你眼力不如以往了
You're losing your eye.
你以前扔得可比這準多了
You used to be able to pitch better than that.
你好  是的  怎么了  斯威尼
Hello? Yeah. What? Sweeney?
有什么我能幫忙的嗎
Well, what can I do for ya?
各大應用市場均可下載
人人美劇APP看美劇就來人人美劇
更新快 無刪減
最大最全的美劇平臺
掃碼即刻下載